A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Grants O-R FA732F
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Ford Foundation Grants - O to R, 1941-2010
  - Rutgers, The State University of New Jersey (06600071), 1965 December 28-1984 April 30 (Reel R4239, Reel R4240, Reel R4815, Reel R5205)
    Partial, terminal support to assist legislative oversight activities regarding education finance and children's services
    Office Of Vice President -Finance & Administration; Urban Poverty Program [UP]
    $1,555,000.00; $1,555,000.00
  - Rutgers, The State University of New Jersey (06700022), 1966 November 22-1967 April 21 (Reel R1808)
    $8,404.8; $8,404.8
  - Rutgers, The State University of New Jersey (06700290), 1967 July 01-1970 June 30 (Reel R1185)
    Cooperative education program for prospective vocational- technical education teachers
    $67,800.00; $67,800.00
  - Rutgers, The State University of New Jersey (06900321), 1969 April 28-1970 April 27 (Reel R1629)
    Research on the housing of welfare recipients
    $96,900.00; $94,562.56
  - Rutgers, The State University of New Jersey (06900522), 1969 July 01-1971 June 30 (Reel R2004)
    $89,800.00; $62,023.59
  - Rutgers, The State University of New Jersey (06900572), 1969 July 15-1970 July 14 (Reel R1639)
    Supp. For admin. & faculty implement. Prog. To provide manage. & tech. Asst to minority entrepreneurs (newark-camden-patterson)
    $65,400.00; $65,400.00
    Brezenoff, Stanley N.
  - Rutgers, The State University of New Jersey (06900667), 1969 July 01-1969 December 31 (Reel R1448)
    Support of a conference to explore the issues involved in the relationship between social science and public policy
    $29,580.35; $29,580.35
  - Rutgers, The State University of New Jersey (07000289), 1970 May 01-1970 October 31 (Reel R1128)
    Comparative study of municipal conservation commissions in the northeastern states
    $14,760.00; $9,710.04
  - Rutgers, The State University of New Jersey (07000593), 1970 (Reel R1706)
    $3,450.00; $3,450.00
  - Rutgers, The State University of New Jersey (07100261), 1971 September 01-1972 August 31 (Reel R1729)
    $6,090.00; $6,090.00
  - Rutgers, The State University of New Jersey (07100292), 1971 April 23-1973 June 11 (Reel R1172)
    Support for extension of the newark watershed study
  - Rutgers, The State University of New Jersey (07300096), 1973 January 01-1977 December 31 (Reel R2108, Reel R2109)
    Comparative study of social control of adolescent misbehavior in advanced industrial societies
    $145,500.00; $145,415.84
  - Rutgers, The State University of New Jersey (07300152), 1973 January 01-1980 October 01 (Reel R2905)
    General support for the eagleton institute of politics center for the american woman and politics
    $324,000.00; $324,000.00
  - Rutgers, The State University of New Jersey (07450249), 1974 February 14-1975 February 13 (Reel R1203)
    Support for a conference on women in the americas march 18-23,1974
    $5,000.00; $4,993.70
  - Rutgers, The State University of New Jersey (07500231), 1975 March 01-1977 December 31 (Reel R2415)
    Study of judicial involement in school finance reform in new jersey
    $24,300.00; $24,300.00
  - Rutgers, The State University of New Jersey (07750182), 1977 May 01-1979 April 30 (Reel R2902)
    To provide partial support of a conference to discuss issues and problems related to the "just deserts" model of punishment
    $5,000.00; $2,991.68
  - Rutgers, The State University of New Jersey (07750323), 1977 April 15-1977 October 14 (Reel R1272)
    Research to produce model legislation for state payments in lieu of taxes to municipalities to be conducted by the office of newark
    $10,000.00; $7,963.93
  - Rutgers, The State University of New Jersey (07800202), 1978 February 15-1980 February 14 (Reel R2872)
    Support of an analysis of legal doctrines and compliance standardsused in school finance litigation
    $82,650.00; $82,650.00
  - Rutgers, The State University of New Jersey (07950466), 1979 June 01-1979 August 31 (Reel R3648)
    Partial support of a two day conference on cameras and the courts
  - Rutgers, The State University of New Jersey (07950643), 1979 August 15-1979 November 14 (Reel R3684)
    Partial support of a one day conference dealing with the upcoming negotiations of the world administrative radio conf. In geneva
    Friendly, Fred W.
  - Rutgers, The State University of New Jersey (08150195), 1981 January 01-1981 October 01 (Reel R3753)
    Partial support of conference on u.s.-asian economic relations sponsored by the university's center for asian economic research
  - Rutgers, The State University of New Jersey (08150517), 1981 May 01-1981 December 31 (Reel R2931, Reel R5104)
    Support services of professor andrew vayda to two indonesian organizations for environmental research/training programs
    $24,100.00; $24,100.00
  - Rutgers, The State University of New Jersey (08250320), 1981 October 01-1982 December 31 (Reel R3638)
    Partial support for publication of conference proceedings on u.s.-asian economic relations
  - Rutgers, The State University of New Jersey (08250410), 1982 January 01-1983 December 31 (Reel R4374)
    To maintain and access the network of organizations and individuals involved in school finance reform
  - Rutgers, The State University of New Jersey (08250688), 1982 April 15-1983 February 28 (Reel R3674)
    Support for planning for improved instruction in mathematics in new jersey secondary schools
    $19,018.00; $19,018.00
  - Rutgers, The State University of New Jersey (08250866), 1982 June 01-1987 May 31 (Reel R5513, Reel R5507, Reel R5764)
    Support of rutgers university/university of indonesia cooperative program in human ecology
    $77,300.00; $77,300.00
  - Rutgers, The State University of New Jersey (08350290), 1983 January 01-1983 December 31 (Reel R4793)
    Partial support for a graduate student to conduct research on irrigation water management in asia
  - Rutgers, The State University of New Jersey (08350337), 1983 April 01-1985 December 31 (Reel R5760)
    Partial support of conference on "images and identities: the puerto rican in literature"
    $33,764.00; $33,764.00
  - Rutgers, The State University of New Jersey (08450435), 1984 March 01-1985 February 28 (Reel R4409)
    Support of a short course on "human welfare implications of irrigation development" at rutgers, 1984
    $48,940.00; $48,940.00
  - Rutgers, The State University of New Jersey (08450559), 1984 July 01-1986 December 15 (Reel R4586)
    Support of a conference commemorating the enactment of the civil rights act of 1964 and assessing its impact
    $30,000.00; $29,041.81
  - Rutgers, The State University of New Jersey (08550174), 1984 October 01-1985 September 30 (Reel R4780)
    Support for second short course on "human welfare implications of irrigation development" at rutgers, 1985
    $45,200.00; $45,200.00
    Lenton, Roberto
  - Rutgers, The State University of New Jersey (08551052), 1985 October 01-1987 June 30 (Reel R5632)
    Provide support for transcription and cataloguing of audio tapes relating to brotherhood of sleeping car porters
    $18,067.00; $18,067.00
  - Rutgers, the State University of New Jersey (08600462), 1986 April 01-1996 December 31 (Reel R7562)
    Partial support for the center for negotiation and conflict resolution at the newark campus of rutgers
    $928,000.00; $928,000.00
    Arnold, David D.; Forman, Shepard; Neuborne, Helen; Wing, Christine B.
  - Rutgers, The State University of New Jersey (08600826), 1986 July 01-1988 December 31 (Reel R5650)
    Partial support for the reproductive rights law and policy project(rhg)
  - Rutgers, The State University of New Jersey (08750420), 1987 February 01-1988 January 31 (Reel R5755)
    Support for a study of the feasibility of using community foundations to receive court-ordered restitution settlements
    $5,000.00; $4,374.75
  - Rutgers, The State University of New Jersey (08750674), 1987 July 01-1988 June 30 (Reel R5793)
    Support for completion of a study of human capital development in the social sciences in asia
  - Rutgers, The State University of New Jersey (08850912), 1988 July 01-1988 December 31 (Reel R5774)
    Support for two workshops on aspects of policy-oriented agricultural research in the united states and in developing countries
    United States; Developing Countries
  - Rutgers, The State University of New Jersey (08900671), 1989 May 01-1993 June 30 (Reel R6386)
    Support for a meeting of national organizations of women public officials
    Smith, Marcia A.; Zeitlin, June H.
  - Rutgers, The State University of New Jersey (08951333), 1989 September 01-1990 August 31 (Reel R5808)
    Research study by eagleton institute of the saliency of the abortion issue in state and local elections (rhg)
    United States; New Jersey; Virginia
  - Rutgers, the State University of New Jersey (09050791), 1990 April 01-1991 July 01 (Reel R6165)
    Planning & devloping a program on women, violence & human rights at the center for global issues and women's leadership
  - Rutgers, The State University of New Jersey (09051437), 1990 September 01-1992 February 29 (Reel R6362)
    To plan and administer visits to selected u.s. Dispute resolution programs by a group of judicial leaders from india and sri lanka
    $23,260.00; $23,260.00
    Sri Lanka; India
  - Rutgers, The State University of New Jersey (09101043), 1991 July 01-1997 September 30 (Reel R7088)
    Support for the center on women's global leadership
  - Rutgers, The State University of New Jersey (09150409), 1991 February 01-1992 January 31 (Reel R6210)
    Pilot training program in public management & service delivery for local government officials in poland (009)
    Arnold, David D.; Balaran, Paul
  - Rutgers, The State University of New Jersey (09251212), 1992 August 01-1994 May 30 (Reel R6791)
    Partial support for international research symposium on foundations and subsequent conference report
  - Rutgers, The State University of New Jersey (09300886), 1993 July 01-1996 September 30 (Reel R7645)
    Support for an assessment of five community development collaboratives
    Anglin, Roland; DeLille, Keiko I.
    Atlanta (Ga.); Cleveland (Ohio); Miami (Fla.)
  - Rutgers, The State University of New Jersey (09350714), 1993 April 01-1994 March 31 (Reel R6653)
    Media training and assistance for the center for women's global leadership around the 1993 world conference on human rights
  - Rutgers, The State University of New Jersey (09351036), 1993 July 01-1993 August 31 (Reel R6671)
    Support for a review of research on the long-term effects of early childhood education
    $14,800.00; $14,800.00
  - Rutgers, The State University of New Jersey (09351308), 1993 September 01-1995 January 31 (Reel R6796)
    Support for a conference to develop a research agenda on women and american politics
  - Rutgers, The State University of New Jersey (09400611), 1994 February 01-1997 April 28 (Reel R7267)
    To develop a test to measure the effectiveness of service-learning programs and other forms of civic service
    Aguerrebere, Joseph; Beckham, Edgar F.
  - Rutgers, The State University of New Jersey (09450130), 1993 October 01-1995 May 31 (Reel R6872)
    For a pilot program for teacher training to integrate conflict resolution themes & practices into high school u.s. History curricula
  - Rutgers, The State University of New Jersey (09450923), 1994 May 15-1997 December 31 (Reel R7905)
    Support for the global women's studies curriculum and faculty development project at rutgers university
    $55,000.00; $54,728.28
    Petrovich, Janice; Zwerling, L. Steven
  - Rutgers, The State University of New Jersey (09500656), 1995 March 01-1996 June 30 (Reel R7088)
  - Rutgers, The State University of New Jersey (09500789), 1995 May 01-1997 April 30 (Reel R7297)
    For teacher training program to integrate conflict resolution themes & practices into middle and high school u.s. History curricula
  - Rutgers, The State University of New Jersey (09600331), 1995 July 01-1996 April 30 (Reel R6827)
    Support for a workshop on women and aids at the 1995 national forum for women state legislators
    $9,800.00; $9,800.00
  - Rutgers, The State University of New Jersey (09601254), 1996 September 01-1999 January 31 (Reel R8442)
    Support for training and education for community organizers in the northeast
    Anglin, Roland; Smith, Marcia A.
  - Rutgers, The State University of New Jersey (09650222), 1995 November 01-1997 October 31 (Reel R8275)
    Support for a project that integrates women's studies and area studies research
  - Rutgers, The State University of New Jersey (09651035), 1996 July 01-1997 December 31 (Reel R8373)
    Support for an evaluation of the project leap academy
  - Rutgers, the State University of New Jersey (09651374), 1996 July 01-1999 June 30 (Reel R8458)
    Support for research project at the center for the american woman and politics on women members of congress
  - Rutgers, the State University of New Jersey (09700172), 1996 October 01-1999 April 30 (Reel R8454)
    Partial support for development of a women's human rights manual
  - Rutgers, the State University of New Jersey (09700343), 1997 January 01-1999 August 31 (Reel R8413)
    To develop a test to measure the impact of service learning and civic education on civic skills, attitudes, and behavior
    $147,000.00; $147,000.00
  - Rutgers, the State University of New Jersey (09700916), 1997 June 01-2001 December 31 (Reel R8832)
    Support for working on violence against women
    Goswami, Roshmi, Dr.; McDaniel, Jr., Joseph M.
  - Rutgers, The State University of New Jersey (09701169), 1997 May 01-1999 April 30 (Reel R8093)
    Partial support for a project on downsizing military budgets
  - Rutgers, The State University of New Jersey (09701601), 1997 August 01-1999 March 31 (Reel R7989)
    Support for strengthening women's rights & political participation in religious & cultural contexts of muslim communities worldwide
    PSJ - Office of the Vice President; Human Rights
    Ispahani, Mahnaz Z.; Phillips, Barbara
  - Rutgers, the State University of New Jersey (09701613), 1997 June 01-2005 June 30 (Reel R9145)
    Support for the partnership for trust in government
    $1,280,000.00; $1,280,000.00
  - Rutgers, the State University of New Jersey (09801160), 1998 May 01-2004 December 31 (Reel R9197)
    Support for research on race and gender discrimination in major metropolitan employment markets
    United States; Affirmative action programs -- Law and legislation -- United States; Race Discrimination--Law and legislation--United States; Sex discrimination
  - Rutgers, the State University of New Jersey (09801243), 1998 June 01-2000 June 30 (Reel R8413)
    Support for research on brownfields and for a pilot project linking community groups to a metropolitan issues policy institute
    United States; Community development -- United States; Sustainable development--United States; Brownfields -- United States
  - Rutgers, the State University of New Jersey (09801425), 1998 October 01-1999 September 30 (Reel R8303)
    Support for the latin american studies program's project on "writers at the border"
    $84,100.00; $82,683.69
    United States; Latin America; Writing--Study and teaching--Latin Americans
  - Rutgers, The State University of New Jersey (09851920), 1998 October 01-1999 September 30 (Reel R8275)
    Support for strengthening the fragile families initiative's communications strategy
    $75,000.00; $68,305.85
    United States; Child welfare -- United States; Family policy -- United States; Dysfunctional families--United States
  - Rutgers, the State University of New Jersey (09901000), 1999 April 01-2000 December 31 (Reel R8523)
    Support for a worldwide conference examining gender relations in african post-conflict situations
    West Africa (Lagos); Southern Africa (Johannesburg); Human Rights
    $100,000.00; $99,219.71
    Aidoo, Akwasi; Brown, Alice L.; Ispahani, Mahnaz Z.
    Africa; Global; Peace--Citizen participation--Congresses; Civil-military relations; Conflict management -- Congresses
  - Rutgers, the State University of New Jersey (09901165), 1999 August 01-2001 June 30 (Reel R9011)
    To support a scholar-in-residence program, "unmapping the myths: distinguished african women"
    West Africa (Lagos); Education, Sexuality, Religion
    $121,000.00; $115,288.91
    Opoku-Mensah, Aida; Volkman, Toby Alice
    Africa; Area studies -- Africa; Africa -- Study and teaching; Women--Study and teaching--Africa
  - Rutgers, the State University of New Jersey (09901524), 1999 July 01-2001 December 31 (Reel R8845)
    Support for the institutionalization of the institute for women's leadership consortium
    United States; Women's studies--United States; Curriculum planning
  - Rutgers, the State University of New Jersey (09901826), 1999 September 01-2002 May 31 (Reel R8972)
    Core support for rutgers' center for negotiation and conflict resolution
    United States; Conflict management--Study and teaching -- United States; Dispute resolution (Law) -- Study and teaching -- United States
  - Rutgers, the State University of New Jersey (10000951), 2000 January 01-2002 February 28 (Reel R8891)
    Support for data gathering and communications activities related to the strengthening fragile families initiative
    United States; Dysfunctional families--United States; Family policy -- United States; Fathers; Parenting
  - Rutgers, the State University of New Jersey (10050874), 2000 March 01-2002 August 31 (Reel R9024)
    To conduct a study of youth oriented technology centers serving urban youths
    United States; Community development -- United States; Youth--Services for--United States
  - Rutgers, the State University of New Jersey (10050879), 2000 January 01-2001 April 30 (Reel R8738)
    Support for beijing +5 conference activities
  - Rutgers, the State University of New Jersey (10051201), 2000 February 01-2002 March 31 (Reel R8951)
    Support to the community university consortium for regional environmental justice to convene a conference entitled "community-based research for environmental justice: workshops from the field"
    Puerto Rico; New Jersey; New York (State); Environmental law -- Congresses; Community development -- Environmental aspects -- United States
  - Rutgers, the State University of New Jersey (10051398), 2000 August 15-2002 June 30 (Reel R9032)
    Support to analyze links between types of mortgage lending and racial discrimination in atlanta, georgia neighborhoods
    $55,000.00; $51,756.49
    Georgia; Mortgage Loans--Georgia; Poor--Housing--United States; Home ownership -- United States; Minorities--Housing--United States; Discrimination in Housing -- United States
  - Rutgers, the State University of New Jersey (10150255), 2000 October 01-2001 September 30 (Reel R9085)
    Support for research and publications regarding race and gender discrimination in major metropolitan employment markets
    United States; Sex Discrimination in Employment--United States--Research; Discrimination in Employment -- Law and legislation -- United States; Minorities--Employment--United States
  - Rutgers, the State University of New Jersey (10150328), 2000 December 15-2001 December 14 (Reel R8970)
    Support for the University's Center for Urban Policy Research to assist the Interfaith Education Fund in its efforts to create a strategic plan to build capacity to manage its organizational growth
    Economic Development; Education, Sexuality, Religion
    Manus, Mara A.; Driver, Cyrus
    United States; Community development -- Study and teaching
  - Rutgers, the State University of New Jersey (10150366), 2000 November 01-2001 October 31 (Reel R8909)
    Support for the global civil society research project of the University's Walt Whitman Center for the Culture and Politics of Democracy
    Global; Civil society -- Global -- Research
  - Rutgers, the State University of New Jersey (10151741), 2001 May 01-2001 December 31 (Reel R8875)
    For activities to both deepen and strengthen the women's human rights network in its work on the intersection of gender, race and class in connection with the World Conference Against Racism
    Global; Women's rights; Intergroup relations
  - Rutgers, the State University of New Jersey (10351287), 2003 June 01-2004 September 30 (Reel R9132)
    For research on how Salvadoran immigrants can improve the use of remittances to strengthen their collective ties in the United States and contribute to development of their hometowns in El Salvador
    Mexico and Central America (Mexico City); Human Rights; Education, Sexuality, Religion
    Myhre, David; Higashi, Taryn; Balan, Jorge
    El Salvador; United States
  - Ruth Escobar Promocoes Culturais (08151060), 1981 August 25-1983 August 24 (Reel R5512)
    Support of the ruth escobar prison theatre project (brazil)
  - Ryazan Regional Branch of the Russian Historical-Educational Human Rights Defending and Charitable Society "memorial" (09750700), 1997 March 01-1998 February 28 (Reel R7896, Reel R8387)
    Support for the development of an internet site for russian human rights organizations